<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="cfr.xsl"?>
<CFRGRANULE xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="CFRMergedXML.xsd">
    <FDSYS>
        <CFRTITLE>27</CFRTITLE>
        <CFRTITLETEXT>Alcohol, Tobacco Products and Firearms</CFRTITLETEXT>
        <VOL>1</VOL>
        <DATE>2024-04-01</DATE>
        <ORIGINALDATE>2024-04-01</ORIGINALDATE>
        <COVERONLY>false</COVERONLY>
        <TITLE>BASIC PERMIT REQUIREMENTS UNDER THE FEDERAL ALCOHOL ADMINISTRATION ACT, NONINDUSTRIAL USE OF DISTILLED SPIRITS AND WINE, BULK SALES AND BOTTLING OF DISTILLED SPIRITS</TITLE>
        <GRANULENUM>1</GRANULENUM>
        <HEADING>PART 1</HEADING>
        <ANCESTORS>
            <PARENT HEADING="Title 27" SEQ="2">Alcohol, Tobacco Products and Firearms</PARENT>
            <PARENT HEADING="CHAPTER I" SEQ="1">ALCOHOL AND TOBACCO TAX AND TRADE BUREAU, DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY</PARENT>
            <PARENT HEADING="SUBCHAPTER A" SEQ="0">ALCOHOL</PARENT>
        </ANCESTORS>
    </FDSYS>
    <PART>
        <EAR>Pt. 1</EAR>
        <HD SOURCE="HED">PART 1—BASIC PERMIT REQUIREMENTS UNDER THE FEDERAL ALCOHOL ADMINISTRATION ACT, NONINDUSTRIAL USE OF DISTILLED SPIRITS AND WINE, BULK SALES AND BOTTLING OF DISTILLED SPIRITS</HD>
        <CONTENTS>
            <SUBPART>
                <HD SOURCE="HED">Subpart A—Scope</HD>
                <SECHD>Sec.</SECHD>
                <SECTNO>1.1</SECTNO>
                <SUBJECT>General.</SUBJECT>
                <SECTNO>1.2</SECTNO>
                <SUBJECT>Territorial extent.</SUBJECT>
                <SECTNO>1.3</SECTNO>
                <SUBJECT>Forms prescribed.</SUBJECT>
                <SECTNO>1.4</SECTNO>
                <SUBJECT>Delegations of the Administrator.</SUBJECT>
            </SUBPART>
            <SUBPART>
                <HD SOURCE="HED">Subpart B—Definitions</HD>
                <SECTNO>1.10</SECTNO>
                <SUBJECT>Meaning of terms.</SUBJECT>
            </SUBPART>
            <SUBPART>
                <HD SOURCE="HED">Subpart C—Basic Permits</HD>
                <SUBJGRP>
                    <HD SOURCE="HED">When Required</HD>
                    <SECTNO>1.20</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Importers.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.21</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Domestic producers, rectifiers, blenders, and warehousemen.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.22</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Wholesalers.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.23</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>State agencies.</SUBJECT>
                </SUBJGRP>
                <SUBJGRP>
                    <HD SOURCE="HED">Persons Entitled to Basic Permits</HD>
                    <SECTNO>1.24</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Qualifications of applicants.</SUBJECT>
                </SUBJGRP>
                <SUBJGRP>
                    <HD SOURCE="HED">Applications for Permits</HD>
                    <SECTNO>1.25</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>General.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.26</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Incomplete or incorrectly executed applications.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.27</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Change in ownership, management, or control of the applicant.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.29</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Individual plant or premises.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.30</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Power of attorney; Form 5000.8 (1534).</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.31</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Denial of permit applications.</SUBJECT>
                </SUBJGRP>
                <SUBJGRP>
                    <HD SOURCE="HED">Authorization</HD>
                    <SECTNO>1.35</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Authority to issue, amend, deny, suspend, revoke, or annul basic permits.</SUBJECT>
                </SUBJGRP>
                <SUBJGRP>
                    <HD SOURCE="HED">Amendment and Duration of Basic Permits</HD>
                    <SECTNO>1.40</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Change of name.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.41</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Change of address.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.42</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Change in ownership, management, or control of business.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.43</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Duration of permits.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.44</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Automatic termination of permits.</SUBJECT>
                </SUBJGRP>
                <SUBJGRP>
                    <HD SOURCE="HED">Revocation, Suspension, or Annulment of Basic Permits</HD>
                    <SECTNO>1.50</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Revocation or suspension.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.51</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Annulment.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.52</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Disposition of stocks of alcoholic beverages upon revocation, annulment, or automatic termination of basic permit.</SUBJECT>
                </SUBJGRP>
                <SUBJGRP>
                    <HD SOURCE="HED">Miscellaneous</HD>
                    <SECTNO>1.55</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Recalling permits for correction.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.56</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Oaths and affirmations.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.57</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Procedure.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.58</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Filing of permits.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.59</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Public information as to applications acted upon.</SUBJECT>
                </SUBJGRP>
            </SUBPART>
            <SUBPART>
                <HD SOURCE="HED">Subpart D—Nonindustrial Use of Distilled Spirits and Wine</HD>
                <SUBJGRP>
                    <HD SOURCE="HED">Uses Regarded as Industrial</HD>
                    <SECTNO>1.60</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Use of distilled spirits.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.61</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Use of wine.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.62</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Use of distilled spirits or wine for experimental purposes and in manufacture of nonbeverage products.</SUBJECT>
                </SUBJGRP>
                <SUBJGRP>
                    <HD SOURCE="HED">Uses Classed as Nonindustrial</HD>
                    <SECTNO>1.70</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>General.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.71</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Distilled spirits in containers of a capacity of one gallon or less.</SUBJECT>
                </SUBJGRP>
            </SUBPART>
            <SUBPART>
                <HD SOURCE="HED">Subpart E—Bulk Sales and Bottling of Distilled Spirits</HD>
                <SUBJGRP>
                    <HD SOURCE="HED">Bulk Sales and Bottling</HD>
                    <SECTNO>1.80</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Sales of distilled spirits in bulk.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.81</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Importation of distilled spirits in bulk.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.82</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Acquiring or receiving distilled spirits in bulk for redistillation, processing, rectification, warehousing, or warehousing and bottling.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.83</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Acquiring or receiving distilled spirits in bulk for addition to wine.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.84</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Acquisition of distilled spirits in bulk by Government agencies.</SUBJECT>
                </SUBJGRP>
                <SUBJGRP>
                    <HD SOURCE="HED">Warehouse Receipts</HD>
                    <SECTNO>1.90</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Distilled spirits in bulk.</SUBJECT>
                    <SECTNO>1.91</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Bottled distilled spirits.</SUBJECT>
                </SUBJGRP>
                <SUBJGRP>
                    <HD SOURCE="HED">Sales of Distilled Spirits for Industrial Use</HD>
                    <SECTNO>1.95</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>General.</SUBJECT>
                </SUBJGRP>
            </SUBPART>
        </CONTENTS>
        <AUTH>
            <HD SOURCE="HED">Authority:</HD>
            <P>27 U.S.C. 203, 204, 206, 211 unless otherwise noted.</P>
        </AUTH>
        <SOURCE>
            <HD SOURCE="HED">Source:</HD>
            <P>T.D. ATF-373, 61 FR 26098, May 24, 1996, unless otherwise noted.</P>
        </SOURCE>
        <EDNOTE>
            <HD SOURCE="HED">Editorial Note:</HD>
            <P>Nomenclature changes to part 1 appear by T.D. ATF-463, 66 FR 42733, Aug. 15, 2001.</P>
        </EDNOTE>
        <SUBPART>
            <PRTPAGE P="6"/>
            <HD SOURCE="HED">Subpart A—Scope</HD>
            <SECTION>
                <SECTNO>§ 1.1</SECTNO>
                <SUBJECT>General.</SUBJECT>
                <P>(a) The regulations in this part relate to requirements governing the issuance, amendment, denial, revocation, suspension, automatic termination, and annulment of basic permits and the duration of permits, except that the provisions of part 71, Rules of Practice in Permit Proceedings, of this chapter are hereby made applicable to administrative proceedings with respect to the application for, and to the suspension, revocation, or annulment of, basic permits under the Federal Alcohol Administration Act.</P>
                <P>(b) The regulations in this part also specify what uses of distilled spirits and wine are “nonindustrial,” as that term is used in section 117 of the Federal Alcohol Administration Act (27 U.S.C. 211). Finally, this part, in accordance with section 106 of the Federal Alcohol Administration Act (27 U.S.C. 206), contains the substantive requirements relative to bulk sales and bottling of distilled spirits under the Federal Alcohol Administration Act, including the terms of warehouse receipts for distilled spirits in bulk. No procedural requirements are prescribed.</P>
            </SECTION>
            <SECTION>
                <SECTNO>§ 1.2</SECTNO>
                <SUBJECT>Territorial extent.</SUBJECT>
                <P>The provisions of this part are applicable to the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia and Puerto Rico.</P>
            </SECTION>
            <SECTION>
                <SECTNO>§ 1.3</SECTNO>
                <SUBJECT>Forms prescribed.</SUBJECT>
                <P>(a) The appropriate TTB officer is authorized to prescribe all forms required by this part. All of the information called for in each form shall be furnished as indicated by the headings on the form and the instructions on or pertaining to the form. In addition, information called for in each form shall be furnished as required by this part. The form will be filed in accordance with the instructions for the form.</P>
                <P>
                    (b) Forms prescribed by this part are available for printing through the TTB Web site (
                    <E T="03">http://www.ttb.gov</E>
                    ) or by mailing a request to the Alcohol and Tobacco Tax and Trade Bureau, National Revenue Center, 550 Main Street, Room 1516, Cincinnati, OH 45202.
                </P>
                <CITA>[T.D. ATF-373, 61 FR 26098, May 24, 1996, as amended by T.D. ATF-416, 64 FR 49985, Sept. 15, 1999; T.D. TTB-44, 71 FR 16920, Apr. 4, 2006]</CITA>
            </SECTION>
            <SECTION>
                <SECTNO>§ 1.4</SECTNO>
                <SUBJECT>Delegations of the Administrator.</SUBJECT>
                <P>
                    Most of the regulatory authorities of the Administrator contained in this part are delegated to appropriate TTB officers. These TTB officers are specified in TTB Order 1135.1, Delegation of the Administrator's Authorities in 27 CFR Part 1, Basic Permit Requirements Under the Federal Alcohol Administration Act, Nonindustrial Use of Distilled Spirits and Wine, Bulk Sales and Bottling of Distilled Spirits. You may obtain a copy of this order by accessing the TTB Web site (
                    <E T="03">http://www.ttb.gov</E>
                    ) or by mailing a request to the Alcohol and Tobacco Tax and Trade Bureau, National Revenue Center, 550 Main Street, Room 1516, Cincinnati, OH 45202.
                </P>
                <CITA>[T.D. TTB-44, 71 FR 16920, Apr. 4, 2006]</CITA>
            </SECTION>
        </SUBPART>
        <SUBPART>
            <HD SOURCE="HED">Subpart B—Definitions</HD>
            <SECTION>
                <SECTNO>§ 1.10</SECTNO>
                <SUBJECT>Meaning of terms.</SUBJECT>
                <P>As used in this part, unless the context otherwise requires, terms shall have the meaning ascribed in this part.</P>
                <P>
                    <E T="03">Act.</E>
                     The Federal Alcohol Administration Act.
                </P>
                <P>
                    <E T="03">Administrator.</E>
                     The Administrator, Alcohol and Tobacco Tax and Trade Bureau, Department of the Treasury, Washington, DC.
                </P>
                <P>
                    <E T="03">Alcohol.</E>
                     Ethyl alcohol distilled at or above 190° proof.
                </P>
                <P>
                    <E T="03">Applicant.</E>
                     Any person who has filed an application for a basic permit under the Federal Alcohol Administration Act with the appropriate TTB officer.
                </P>
                <P>
                    <E T="03">Appropriate TTB officer.</E>
                     An officer or employee of the Alcohol and Tobacco Tax and Trade Bureau (TTB) authorized to perform any functions relating to the administration or enforcement of this part by TTB Order 1135.1, Delegation of the Administrator's Authorities in 27 CFR Part 1, Basic Permit Requirements Under the Federal Alcohol Administration Act, Nonindustrial Use of Distilled Spirits and Wine, Bulk Sales and Bottling of Distilled Spirits.
                    <PRTPAGE P="7"/>
                </P>
                <P>
                    <E T="03">Basic permit.</E>
                     A document issued under the Act authorizing a person to engage in activities at a particular location.
                </P>
                <P>
                    <E T="03">Brandy.</E>
                     Brandy or wine spirits for addition to wines as permitted by internal revenue law.
                </P>
                <P>
                    <E T="03">Distilled spirits.</E>
                     Section 117(a) of the Federal Alcohol Administration Act (27 U.S.C. 211(a)) defines “distilled spirits” as ethyl alcohol, hydrated oxide of ethyl, spirits of wine, whiskey, rum, brandy, gin, and other distilled spirits, including all dilutions and mixtures thereof for nonindustrial use.
                </P>
                <P>
                    <E T="03">In bulk.</E>
                     Distilled spirits in containers having a capacity in excess of one wine gallon.
                </P>
                <P>
                    <E T="03">Malt beverage.</E>
                     A beverage made by the alcoholic fermentation of an infusion or decoction, or combination of both, in potable brewing water, of malted barley with hops, or their parts, or their products, and with or without other malted cereals, and with or without the addition of unmalted or prepared cereals, other carbohydrates or products prepared therefrom, and with or without the addition of carbon dioxide, and with or without other wholesome products suitable for human food consumption. Standards applying to the use of processing methods and flavors in malt beverage production appear in § 7.11 of this chapter.
                </P>
                <P>
                    <E T="03">Other term.</E>
                     Any other term defined in the Federal Alcohol Administration Act and used in this part shall have the same meaning assigned to it by the Act.
                </P>
                <P>
                    <E T="03">Permittee.</E>
                     Any person holding a basic permit issued under the Federal Alcohol Administration Act.
                </P>
                <P>
                    <E T="03">Person.</E>
                     Any individual, partnership, joint-stock company, business trust, association, corporation, or other form of business enterprise, including a receiver, trustee, or liquidating agent.
                </P>
                <P>
                    <E T="03">Resale at wholesale.</E>
                     A sale to any trade buyer.
                </P>
                <P>
                    <E T="03">Trade buyer.</E>
                     Any person who is a wholesaler or retailer of distilled spirits, wine, or malt beverages.
                </P>
                <P>
                    <E T="03">Wine.</E>
                     Section 117(a) of the Federal Alcohol Administration Act (27 U.S.C. 211(a)) defines “wine” as any of the following products for nonindustrial use that contain not less than 7 percent and not more than 24 percent alcohol by volume:
                </P>
                <P>(1) Wine as defined in section 610 and section 617 of the Revenue Act of 1918 (26 U.S.C. 5381-5392); and</P>
                <P>(2) Other alcoholic beverages not so defined, but made in the manner of wine, including sparkling and carbonated wine, wine made from condensed grape must, wine made from other agricultural products than the juice of sound, ripe grapes, imitation wine, compounds sold as wine, vermouth, cider, perry, and sake.</P>
                <P>
                    <E T="03">Wine gallon.</E>
                     The liquid measure equivalent to the volume of 231 cubic inches.
                </P>
                <CITA>[T.D. ATF-373, 61 FR 26098, May 24, 1996. Redesignated and amended by T.D. ATF-416, 64 FR 49985, Sept. 15, 1999; T.D. TTB-44, 71 FR 16920, Apr. 4, 2006; T.D. TTB-91, 76 FR 5476, Feb. 1, 2011; T.D. TTB-145, 81 FR 94196, Dec. 22, 2016]</CITA>
            </SECTION>
        </SUBPART>
        <SUBPART>
            <HD SOURCE="HED">Subpart C—Basic Permits</HD>
            <EDNOTE>
                <HD SOURCE="HED">Editorial Note:</HD>
                <P>Nomenclature changes to subpart C of part 1 appear by T.D. ATF-416, 64 FR 49985, Sept. 15, 1999.</P>
            </EDNOTE>
            <SUBJGRP>
                <HD SOURCE="HED">When Required</HD>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.20</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Importers.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>No person, except pursuant to a basic permit issued under the Act, shall:</P>
                    <P>(a) Engage in the business of importing into the United States distilled spirits, wine, or malt beverages; or</P>
                    <P>(b) While so engaged, sell, offer or deliver for sale, contract to sell, or ship, in interstate or foreign commerce, directly or indirectly or through an affiliate, distilled spirits, wine, or malt beverages so imported.</P>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.21</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Domestic producers, rectifiers, blenders, and warehousemen.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>No person, except pursuant to a basic permit issued under the Act, shall:</P>
                    <P>(a) Engage in the business of distilling distilled spirits, producing wine, rectifying or blending distilled spirits or wine, or bottling, or warehousing and bottling, distilled spirits; or</P>
                    <P>
                        (b) While so engaged, sell, offer or deliver for sale, contract to sell, or ship, 
                        <PRTPAGE P="8"/>
                        in interstate or foreign commerce, directly or indirectly or through an affiliate, distilled spirits or wine so distilled, produced, rectified, blended, or bottled, or warehoused and bottled.
                    </P>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.22</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Wholesalers.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>No person, except pursuant to a basic permit issued under the Act, shall:</P>
                    <P>(a) Engage in the business of purchasing for resale at wholesale, distilled spirits, wine, or malt beverages; or,</P>
                    <P>(b) While so engaged, receive, sell, offer or deliver for sale, contract to sell, or ship in interstate or foreign commerce, directly or indirectly or through an affiliate, distilled spirits, wine, or malt beverages so purchased.</P>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.23</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>State agencies.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>This subpart shall not apply to any agency of a State or political subdivision thereof or to any officer or employee of any such agency, and no such agency or officer or employee thereof shall be required to obtain a basic permit under this subpart.</P>
                </SECTION>
            </SUBJGRP>
            <SUBJGRP>
                <HD SOURCE="HED">Persons Entitled to Basic Permits</HD>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.24</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Qualifications of applicants.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>The application of any person shall be granted and the permit issued by the appropriate TTB officer if the applicant proves to the satisfaction of the appropriate TTB officer that:</P>
                    <P>(a) Such person (or in case of a corporation, any of its officers, directors, or principal stockholders) has not, within 5 years prior to the date of application, been convicted of a felony under Federal or State law, and has not, within 3 years prior to date of application, been convicted of a misdemeanor under any Federal law relating to liquor, including the taxation thereof; and</P>
                    <P>(b) Such person, by reason of the person's business experience, financial standing or trade connections, is likely to commence operations as a distiller, warehouseman and bottler, rectifier, wine producer, wine blender, importer, or wholesaler, as the case may be, within a reasonable period and to maintain such operations in conformity with Federal law; and</P>
                    <P>(c) The operations proposed to be conducted by such person are not in violation of the law of the State in which they are to be conducted.</P>
                </SECTION>
            </SUBJGRP>
            <SUBJGRP>
                <HD SOURCE="HED">Applications for Permits</HD>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.25</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>General.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>Applications for basic permits to engage in any of the operations set forth in §§ 1.20 to 1.22 must be made on TTB Form 5100.24, or 5100.18, verified as required by § 1.56, and will be accompanied by such affidavits, documents, and other supporting data, as the appropriate TTB officer may require. The application will include all data, written statements, affidavits, documents, or other evidence submitted in support of the application, or upon a hearing.</P>
                    <CITA>[T.D. ATF-416, 64 FR 49985, Sept. 15, 1999; T.D. ATF-416a, 64 FR 54776, Oct. 8, 1999]</CITA>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.26</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Incomplete or incorrectly executed applications.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>Incomplete or incorrectly executed applications will not be acted upon, but the applicant shall be entitled to file a new application without prejudice, or to complete the application already filed.</P>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.27</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Change in ownership, management, or control of the applicant.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>In the event of any change in the ownership, management, or control of the applicant (in case of a corporation, any change in the officers, directors, or persons holding more than 10 percent of the corporate stock), after the date of filing of any application for a basic permit and prior to final action on such application, the applicant shall notify the appropriate TTB officer immediately of such change.</P>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.29</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Individual plant or premises.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>An application for a basic permit must be filed, and permit issued, to cover each individual plant or premises where any of the businesses specified in section 103 of the Act is engaged in.</P>
                    <CITA>[T.D. ATF-416, 64 FR 49985, Sept. 15, 1999]</CITA>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.30</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Power of attorney; Form 5000.8 (1534).</SUBJECT>
                    <P>
                        If the application and other documents in support of such application 
                        <PRTPAGE P="9"/>
                        are signed by an attorney in fact of an individual, partnership, association, or corporation, or by one of the members of a copartnership or association, or, in the case of a corporation by an officer or other person not authorized by the corporation's bylaws or by its board of directors to sign such applications and supporting documents, the applications must be supported by a duly authenticated copy of the power of attorney conferring authority upon the person signing the documents to execute the same. Such powers of attorney will be executed on Form 5000.8 (1534).
                    </P>
                    <APPRO>(Approved by the Office of Management and Budget under control number 1512-0079)</APPRO>
                    <CITA>[T.D. ATF-373, 61 FR 26098, May 24, 1996, as amended by T.D. ATF-416, 64 FR 49985, Sept. 15, 1999]</CITA>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.31</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Denial of permit applications.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>If, upon examination of any application for a basic permit, the appropriate TTB officer has reason to believe that the applicant is not entitled to such a permit, the appropriate TTB officer shall institute proceedings for the denial of the application in accordance with the procedure set forth in part 71 of this chapter.</P>
                </SECTION>
            </SUBJGRP>
            <SUBJGRP>
                <HD SOURCE="HED">Authorization</HD>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.35</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Authority to issue, amend, deny, suspend, revoke, or annul basic permits.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>The authority and power of issuing, amending, or denying basic permits, or amendments thereof, is conferred upon the appropriate TTB officer except as to agency initiated curtailment. The Administrator, upon consideration of appeals on petitions for review in part 71 of this chapter, may order the appropriate TTB officer to issue, deny, suspend, revoke, or annul basic permits.</P>
                    <CITA>[T.D. ATF-416, 64 FR 49985, Sept. 15, 1999]</CITA>
                </SECTION>
            </SUBJGRP>
            <SUBJGRP>
                <HD SOURCE="HED">Amendment and Duration of Basic Permits</HD>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.40</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Change of name.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>In the event of any change in the name (trade or corporate name) of a permittee, or, in the event a permittee desires to engage in operations under an additional trade name, such permittee must file application Form 5100.18 for an amended basic permit, which application must be approved, and amended permit issued, before operations may be commenced under the new name.</P>
                    <APPRO>(Approved by the Office of Management and Budget under control number 1512-0090)</APPRO>
                    <CITA>[T.D. ATF-373, 61 FR 26098, May 24, 1996, as amended by T.D. ATF-416, 64 FR 49985, Sept. 15, 1999]</CITA>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.41</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Change of address.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>In the event of a change in address the permittee must file application Form 5100.18 for an amended basic permit.</P>
                    <CITA>[T.D. ATF-373, 61 FR 26098, May 24, 1996, as amended by T.D. ATF-416, 64 FR 49985, Sept. 15, 1999]</CITA>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.42</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Change in ownership, management, or control of business.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>In the event of any change in the ownership, management, or control of any business operated pursuant to a basic permit (if the permittee is a corporation, if any change occurs in the officers, directors, or persons owning or controlling more than 10 percent of the voting stock of said corporation) the permittee shall immediately notify the appropriate TTB officer of such change, giving the names and addresses of all new persons participating in the ownership, management, or control of such business, or in the case of a corporation, the names and addresses of such new officers, directors, or persons owning or controlling more than 10 percent of the voting stock. Notice to the appropriate TTB officer of any such change shall be accompanied or supplemented by such data in reference to the personal or business history of such persons as the appropriate TTB officer may require.</P>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.43</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Duration of permits.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>A basic permit shall continue in effect until suspended, revoked, annulled, voluntarily surrendered, or automatically terminated, as provided in the Act and in this part.</P>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.44</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Automatic termination of permits.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>
                        No basic permit shall be leased, sold, or otherwise voluntarily transferred, 
                        <PRTPAGE P="10"/>
                        and, in the event of such lease, sale, or other voluntary transfer, such basic permit shall automatically terminate thereupon. If any basic permit is transferred by operation of law or if actual or legal control of the permittee is acquired, directly or indirectly whether by stock ownership or in any other manner, by any person, then such permit shall be automatically terminated at the expiration of 30 days thereafter: Provided, That if within such 30-day period application for a new basic permit is made by the transferee or permittee, respectively, then the outstanding basic permit shall continue in effect until such time as the application is finally acted upon.
                    </P>
                </SECTION>
            </SUBJGRP>
            <SUBJGRP>
                <HD SOURCE="HED">Revocation, Suspension, or Annulment of Basic Permits</HD>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.50</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Revocation or suspension.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>Whenever the appropriate TTB officer has reason to believe that any permittee has willfully violated any of the conditions of the permittee's basic permit or has not engaged in the operations authorized by the permit for a period of more than two years, the appropriate TTB officer shall institute proceedings for the revocation or suspension of such permit, in accordance with the procedure set forth in part 71 of this chapter, which part is made applicable to such proceedings.</P>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.51</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Annulment.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>Whenever the appropriate TTB officer has reason to believe that any basic permit was procured through fraud, or misrepresentation or concealment of material fact, the appropriate TTB officer shall institute proceedings for the annulment of such permit in accordance with the procedure set forth in part 71 of this chapter, which part is made applicable to such proceedings.</P>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.52</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Disposition of stocks of alcoholic beverages upon revocation, annulment, or automatic termination of basic permit.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>In the event of the revocation or annulment of a basic permit, pursuant to part 71 of this chapter, or in the event such permit is automatically terminated by operation of law (27 U.S.C. 204(g) and § 1.44 of this part), the appropriate TTB officer may authorize the orderly disposition of stocks of distilled spirits, wines, or malt beverages then held by the permittee or former permittee upon such conditions as may be considered proper.</P>
                </SECTION>
            </SUBJGRP>
            <SUBJGRP>
                <HD SOURCE="HED">Miscellaneous</HD>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.55</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Recalling permits for correction.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>Whenever it shall be discovered that any basic permit has been issued authorizing acts, or combinations of acts, which may not properly, under the law and regulations, as of now or hereafter in force, be authorized, or that any material mistake has occurred in the issuance thereof, the holder of such permit shall forthwith surrender the same for correction or amendment upon demand of the appropriate TTB officer.</P>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.56</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Oaths and affirmations.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>A document must be verified by an oath or affirmation taken before a person authorized by the laws of the United States or by State or local law to administer oaths or affirmations in the jurisdiction where the document is executed when required by:</P>
                    <P>(a) Regulation; or</P>
                    <P>(b) An appropriate TTB officer.</P>
                    <CITA>[T.D. ATF-416, 64 FR 49985, Sept. 15, 1999]</CITA>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.57</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Procedure.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>The procedures prescribed by the rules of practice in permit proceedings (part 71 of this chapter) are applicable to administrative proceedings for the issuance, amendment, denial, revocation, suspension, or annulment of basic permits, the issuance of subpoenas and the taking of depositions under the Act.</P>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.58</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Filing of permits.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>
                        Every person receiving a basic permit under the provisions of this part must maintain the permit at the place of business covered by the permit and make it available upon the request of the appropriate TTB officer. Every person required to obtain a basic permit as an importer under § 1.20 must, when importing distilled spirits, wine, or malt beverages under that permit and filing TTB data electronically, file the 
                        <PRTPAGE P="11"/>
                        number of the permit with U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) along with the filing of the customs entry. Regardless of the method of filing, every importer must make the permit available upon request by the appropriate TTB officer or a customs officer.
                    </P>
                    <CITA>[T.D. TTB-145, 81 FR 94196, Dec. 22, 2016]</CITA>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.59</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Public information as to applications acted upon.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>The appropriate TTB officer shall cause to be maintained currently in the appropriate TTB officer's office for public inspection, until the expiration of one year following final action on the application, the following information with respect to each application for basic permit filed:</P>
                    <P>(a) The name, including trade name or names, if any, and the address of the applicant; the kind of permit applied for and the location of the business; whether the applicant is an individual, a partnership or a corporation; if a partnership, the name and address of each partner; if a corporation, the name and address of each of the principal officers and of each stockholder owning 10 percent or more of the corporate stock.</P>
                    <P>(b) The time and place set for any hearing on the application.</P>
                    <P>(c) The final action taken on the application. In the event a hearing is held upon an application for a basic permit, the appropriate TTB officer shall make available for inspection at the appropriate TTB officer's office, upon request therefor: The transcript of the hearing, a copy of the administrative law judge's recommended decision, a copy of the appropriate TTB officer's decision and, in the event of an appeal to the Administrator, the decision on appeal with the reasons given in support thereof.</P>
                    <CITA>[T.D. ATF-373, 61 FR 26098, May 24, 1996, as amended by T.D. ATF-416, 64 FR 49985, Sept. 15, 1999]</CITA>
                </SECTION>
            </SUBJGRP>
        </SUBPART>
        <SUBPART>
            <HD SOURCE="HED">Subpart D—Nonindustrial Use of Distilled Spirits and Wine</HD>
            <SUBJGRP>
                <HD SOURCE="HED">Uses Regarded as Industrial</HD>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.60</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Use of distilled spirits.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>The following uses of distilled spirits are regarded as “industrial” and will be excluded from any application of the term “nonindustrial use.” The use of distilled spirits:</P>
                    <P>(a) Free of tax by, and for the use of, the United States or any governmental agency thereof, any State, any political subdivision of a State, or the District of Columbia, for nonbeverage purposes; or</P>
                    <P>(b) Free of tax for nonbeverage purposes and not for resale or use in the manufacture of any product for sale:</P>
                    <P>(1) For the use of any educational organization described in 26 U.S.C. 170(b)(1)(A)(ii) which is exempt from income tax under 26 U.S.C. 501(a), or for the use of any scientific university or college of learning;</P>
                    <P>(2) For any laboratory for use exclusively in scientific research;</P>
                    <P>(3) For use at any hospital, blood bank, or sanitarium (including use in making analysis or test at such hospital, blood bank, or sanitarium), or at any pathological laboratory exclusively engaged in making analyses, or tests, for hospitals or sanitariums; or</P>
                    <P>(4) For the use of any clinic operated for charity and not for profit (including use in compounding of bona fide medicines for treatment outside of such clinics of patients thereof); or</P>
                    <P>(c) Free of tax, after denaturation of such spirits in the manner prescribed by law for:</P>
                    <P>(1) Use in the manufacture of ether, chloroform, or other definite chemical substance where such distilled spirits are changed into some other chemical substance and do not appear in the finished product; or</P>
                    <P>(2) Any other use in the arts and industries (except for uses prohibited by 26 U.S.C. 5273 (b) or (d)) and for fuel, light, and power.</P>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.61</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Use of wine.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>
                        The following uses of wine are regarded as “industrial” and will be excluded from any application of the term “nonindustrial”. The use of wine:
                        <PRTPAGE P="12"/>
                    </P>
                    <P>(a) Without payment of tax for use in the production of vinegar; or</P>
                    <P>(b) Free of tax for experimental or research purposes by any scientific university, college of learning, or institution of scientific research; or</P>
                    <P>(c) Free of tax for use by the United States or any agency thereof, and for use for analysis, testing, research, or experimentation by the governments of the several States and the District of Columbia or of any political subdivision thereof or by any agency of such governments; or</P>
                    <P>(d) Which has been rendered unfit for beverage use.</P>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.62</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Use of distilled spirits or wine for experimental purposes and in manufacture of nonbeverage products.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>The use of distilled spirits or wine for experimental purposes and in the manufacture of (a) medicinal, pharmaceutical, or antiseptic products, including prescriptions compounded by retail druggists; (b) toilet preparations; (c) flavoring extracts, syrups, or food products; or (d) scientific, chemical, mechanical, or industrial products, provided such products are unfit for beverage use, is regarded as “industrial,” and will be excluded from any application of the term “nonindustrial use.”</P>
                </SECTION>
            </SUBJGRP>
            <SUBJGRP>
                <HD SOURCE="HED">Uses Classed as Nonindustrial</HD>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.70</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>General.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>All uses of distilled spirits and wines, except as provided in §§ 1.60, 1.61, and 1.62 of this part, are regarded as “nonindustrial.” Such “nonindustrial” use shall include, but not be limited to, distilled spirits or wine used for beverage purposes, or in the manufacture, rectification, or blending of alcoholic beverages; or in the preparation of food or drink by a hotel, restaurant, tavern, or similar establishment; or for sacramental purposes; or as a medicine.</P>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.71</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Distilled spirits in containers of a capacity of one gallon or less.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>Distilled spirits in containers of a capacity of one wine gallon or less, except anhydrous alcohol and alcohol which may be withdrawn free of tax under the internal revenue laws, will be deemed to be for nonindustrial use.</P>
                </SECTION>
            </SUBJGRP>
        </SUBPART>
        <SUBPART>
            <HD SOURCE="HED">Subpart E—Bulk Sales and Bottling of Distilled Spirits</HD>
            <SUBJGRP>
                <HD SOURCE="HED">Bulk Sales and Bottling</HD>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.80</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Sales of distilled spirits in bulk.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>It is unlawful for any person to sell, offer to sell, contract to sell, or otherwise dispose of distilled spirits in bulk, for nonindustrial use, except for export or to the classes of persons enumerated in §§ 1.82, 1.83, and 1.84.</P>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.81</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Importation of distilled spirits in bulk.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>It is unlawful for any person to import distilled spirits in bulk, for nonindustrial use, except for sale to or for use by the classes of persons enumerated in §§ 1.82, 1.83 and 1.84.</P>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.82</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Acquiring or receiving distilled spirits in bulk for redistillation, processing, rectification, warehousing, or warehousing and bottling.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>
                        (a) 
                        <E T="03">Proprietors of distilled spirits plants.</E>
                         Persons holding basic permits (issued under subpart B of this part) authorizing the distilling, processing, rectifying, or warehousing and bottling of distilled spirits, or operating permits (issued under § 19.91 and succeeding sections of this chapter) may acquire or receive in bulk and redistill, warehouse, or process distilled spirits, so far as permitted by law.
                    </P>
                    <P>
                        (b) 
                        <E T="03">Proprietors of class 8 customs bonded warehouses.</E>
                         If the permittee operates a class 8 customs bonded warehouse, the permittee may acquire or receive in bulk, and warehouse and bottle, imported distilled spirits, so far as permitted by the customs laws.
                    </P>
                    <SECAUTH>(26 U.S.C. 7805 (68A Stat. 917, as amended); 27 U.S.C. 205 (49 Stat. 981, as amended))</SECAUTH>
                    <CITA>[T.D. ATF-373, 61 FR 26098, May 24, 1996, as amended by T.D. TTB-92, 76 FR 9090, Feb. 16, 2011]</CITA>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.83</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Acquiring or receiving distilled spirits in bulk for addition to wine.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>Persons holding permits as producers and blenders of wine, may, pursuant to such permit, acquire or receive in bulk alcohol or brandy for addition to wines.</P>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <PRTPAGE P="13"/>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.84</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Acquisition of distilled spirits in bulk by Government agencies.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>Any agency of the United States, or of any State or political subdivision thereof, may acquire or receive in bulk, and warehouse and bottle, imported and domestic distilled spirits in conformity with the internal revenue laws.</P>
                </SECTION>
            </SUBJGRP>
            <SUBJGRP>
                <HD SOURCE="HED">Warehouse Receipts</HD>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.90</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Distilled spirits in bulk.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>By the terms of the Act (27 U.S.C. 206), all warehouse receipts for distilled spirits in bulk must require that the warehouseman shall package such distilled spirits, before delivery, in bottles labeled and marked in accordance with law, or deliver such distilled spirits in bulk only to persons to whom it is lawful to sell or otherwise dispose of distilled spirits in bulk.</P>
                </SECTION>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.91</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>Bottled distilled spirits.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>The provisions of the Act, which forbid any person to sell, offer to sell, contract to sell, or otherwise dispose of warehouse receipts for distilled spirits in bulk, do not apply to warehouse receipts for bottled distilled spirits.</P>
                    <CROSSREF>
                        <HD SOURCE="HED">Cross Reference:</HD>
                        <P>For labeling of distilled spirits, see part 5 of this chapter.</P>
                    </CROSSREF>
                </SECTION>
            </SUBJGRP>
            <SUBJGRP>
                <HD SOURCE="HED">Sales of Distilled Spirits for Industrial Use</HD>
                <SECTION>
                    <SECTNO>§ 1.95</SECTNO>
                    <SUBJECT>General.</SUBJECT>
                    <P>Distillers, rectifiers, and other permittees engaged in the sale or other disposition of distilled spirits for nonindustrial use shall not sell or otherwise dispose of distilled spirits in bulk (other than alcohol) for industrial use, unless such distilled spirits are shipped or delivered directly to the industrial user thereof.</P>
                </SECTION>
            </SUBJGRP>
        </SUBPART>
    </PART>
</CFRGRANULE>
